究極のモンスターマシン 沼！
The ultimate monster machine, the Bog!
いよいよ残すは本丸
魔性の３段クルーン
All which remains is its last like of defense, the triple tray!
I'll kill him! I'll kill him right here!
殺す　ここでカイジを
手元の軍資金は あと2000万
Kaiji has 20 million left!
狂気を超えた死闘
Their battle continues beyond reason!
いよいよ最終攻防 突入！
Miraculous Trajectory
20 mil left...
あと2000万
Kaiji...
カイジさん…
いけ
You can do it!
いけ！
決める
I've got this.
ねじ込む
I'll keep shooting them in!
2000万分の玉
20 mil... That means I've got 5,000 shots left.
つまり俺の手持ちは あと5000発
One of twenty makes it past the forest of pins, that's better than setting A.
今 釘の森の通過は
設定以上の20発に１発ぐらい
2000万で
およそ250発くらいの玉が
About 250 of those shots will make it to the trays.
クルーンに流れ込む計算だが
３段目まで行くのは
恐らく そのうちの
But only six or seven of those will make it to the third tray.
６発か７発
わずか６発か７発だ
I've only got six or seven chances.
But those six or seven aren't just dead balls.
だが わずかその６～７発は
この３段目のクルーンを
ただ回って落ちる死に玉じゃない
生きている玉
They live!
王を…
Those balls... Will take the King's head!
王の首を取れる玉
刺客だ
I'll assassinate him!
Ichijou, your spell is already broken!
一条　悪いが
もう破れているんだぜ
お前の魔法は
100パーセント入らない？
A perfect defense?
ああ　あの３段クルーンは
カジノ側の策略の巣
Yeah. The triple tray is completely rigged.
偶然 入るなんていう希望は
排除されている
You need to give up on even hoping you'll make it through on luck.
どういうことだ？
How's it work?
あの３つのクルーン
Of the three trays...
The winning hole for the first and second is in front. Only the third is in back.
１段目と２段目は
手前に当たりの穴がある
だが３段目だけは
奥に当たりがあるだろ
あれは見えにくくしてるんだ
That makes it harder to see.
あ？何をだ？
Huh? See what?
当たり穴の後ろ側
You'll normally lose balls just getting them to the back.
普通なら穴に落ちるルート
そこが わずかに盛り上がっている
But that's just the first of their tricks.
そして玉は当たりを
免れる仕組みだ
They've got it rigged to drop balls, too.
It's so dark in the tray that you can barely see the ridges.
薄暗いクルーンの中
その上 透明の隆起
目をこらしても まず気づかない
You can be looking right at them and still not see them.
How did you figure this out?
どうして
カイジ君は分かったんだ？
この前 おっちゃんが
最後に外した玉
The last ball you lost...
It didn't roll right.
えらく不自然な動きをしていた
横に滑っていくような
It was like it slipped sideways.
あんな動きは
奥に膨らみがなければ あり得ない
There has to be a groove in there.
んお… だが前は？カイジ君
I know you said it's impossible, but how about from the front?
さっき100パーセント入らないと
言ったろ
前から入る可能性だって…
Can't you get it in from the front?
そいつも別の方法で殺してるのさ
They've got another trick for that.
別？それじゃ後ろだけじゃなくて
Another trick? They've got got grooves on the front too?
前にも その盛り上がりが
あるってことか？
いや それでは何年かに一度ある
No. They need a way for the boss to win every few years.
会長たちに当たりを出してもらう
接待の時に対応できない
だから前からの玉は
隆起のガードではなく
So there's no ridges up front.
寝かせで殺した
They just lay those down.
Lay those down?
寝かせ？
The third tray is tilted.
傾いているんだ
あの３段クルーンは
奥にある当たり穴と逆方向 手前に
Tilted away from the winning hole in back, toward the front.
そ… そんなふうには見えないぞ
And you can barely see it that way!
一見 分からないように
してあるのさ　分散して
Yeah. It's split up, so it's hard to spot.
分散？
ああ
It's split up?
There's more than one tilt.
傾斜のポイントを分散してるんだ
俺も最初は気づかなかった
I didn't notice it at first either.
だが何度も あの沼の周りを
嗅ぎ回って気づいた
But watching ball after ball go through it...
Noticing the fine details...
細心にして緻密
傾斜の３分割だ
I saw that it tilts on three points.
３分割… 傾斜を
３つに分けてるってことか？
Three points? So there are three different tilts?
そうだ　１つ目の傾斜は
今言ったクルーンそのものの傾き
Yeah. The tray is tilted.
２つ目は台を手前に寝かせる
The second is the machine itself.
み… ３つ目は？
And the third?
覚えてるか？最後の玉が外れた時
Do you remember what happened when you lost your last ball?
You smashed the machine, and the rest went all over.
ぶっ倒れて そこら中に
玉をぶちまけただろ
あの時 一条が来て
And then Ichijou picked them up.
玉を拾った
It didn't seem like anything at the time,
一見 何でもない行為だが
奴が拾い集めたのは
but he only picked up the balls that landed on that platform.
沼へ下りる階段部分の
玉だけだった
そこら中に転がった玉を無視した
He ignored the ones that rolled off.
He ignored them...
無視した？
じゅうたんの玉は
流れずに止まるからな
The ones which rolled on the carpet stopped on their own.
そ… それじゃ
３つ目の傾きってのは…
So the third tilt...
Yeah. It's the floor that the Bog sits on.
そう　沼が設置された
床だ！
一条が あの階段の玉を
拾わなければ
If he hadn't picked up those balls, I wouldn't have noticed either.
俺も気づかなかった
カラクリを知ってるがゆえに出た
過剰反応
He overreacted because he knows the trick.
あれが致命傷さ
That was his fatal mistake.
Fatal mistake?
致命傷？
あそこから動き出したのさ
That's how I figured out how to beat the Bog!
俺の… 沼攻略
Beat the bog?
攻略？
I'm not even sure myself if it'll really work.
うまくいくかどうか
正直 俺もまだ半信半疑だ
You used to work construction, so I'm asking you.
そこで元土建屋の経験を持つ
おっちゃんに相談があるんだ
どうだ？おっちゃん
How about it, pops?
It's crazy.
バカげてる
おっちゃん！
Pops...
It's crazy, but...
バカげてるが
天才的だ！
It's genius.
カイジ君　起こるぞ
Let's do this, Kaiji!
あの日 話した…
Let's make that miracle happen!
奇跡が！
叩き続けたノックが実る！
Kaiji's knocking bears fruit!
Amidst the corpses of all those sacrificed balls,
憤死！頓死！
圧倒的なムダ玉！
a path to heaven opens!
その死屍累々の彼方に現れる
天へと続く
奇跡の軌道！
A railway to a miracle!
大当たり！
To the jackpot!
１玉 ただ１玉で決せられる
One ball! One ball will settle everything!
すべて！
いけ　いけ
Go! Go!
金が尽きる前に
Do it before we run out of money!
Come on!
頼む！
いけ！あと少し！
いけ！
Go for it! You're almost there!
Keep going!
いけ！
いけー！
It's impossible.
不可能だ
確かに第１ 第２の砦は破られた
Even if the first and second gates are smashed...
滝つぼに
いかに大量の落ち葉が流れ落ち
Even if your balls are sucked in like a waterfall...
吸い込まれようとも
その中の ただ１枚たりとも
No matter how many leaves go over a waterfall, not one floats back up!
滝つぼを逆に上ったりはしない
And your chances of beating the trays are the same!
自明の理　それと同じくらい
あり得ないことだ
あのクルーンの敗北など
Is something wrong?
どういうことだ
What is it?
They're not going in.
行ってない
え？
一度も３段目のクルーンに
玉が行ってない
Not one ball is making it to the third tray!
結構なことじゃないですか
Isn't that a good thing?
いや…
No...
あり得るのか？そんなこと
Could it be?
今 沼は床 台 クルーンとも
手前に傾き
The tray, the Bog itself, and the floor are all tilted forward!
奥にある３段目の当たりに
入らないようにしている
That's to make sure that no balls make it to the back of the third tray!
逆に言えば 当たり穴が手前にある
That makes it easier to make it through the first and second trays!
１段目 ２段目には入りやすい
なのに今まで一度も３段目に
玉が行かないってことは…
So if none have gotten to the third tray...
All right! He made it through the first tray!
やった！１段目クリア！
Here we go!
きたぜ！久々に２段目
He's finally back to the second tray!
Go! Go!
いけ　いけ…
Go!
いけ…
いけ！
Go!
このままや！このまま３段目に…
That's it! Make it to the third tray!
いけー！
きたー！
道は… 道は…
Will it open!? Will the path open!?
道は開かれるのか！
ま… まさか
Impossible...
入るはずが…
It can't happen...
そんなこと あり得ない
It's impossible!
そんなこと…
That can't happen!
What's going on!?
何だ この目は？
運否天賦に賭けた奴の目じゃない
Even if it's slim... It seems like there's a chance...
わずかだが
入ることに確信があるような…
ま… まさか
Impossible!
いや！
It missed! Great!
外した　よし
あのコブを越えた玉は
あとは傾斜を下り
Once it's come back down, it'll never climb that slope again!
手前の外れの穴へ落ちる
もう二度と上らない
The tilt will keep it at the bottom!
手前に傾いた この傾斜を
な… 何！
店長！
What!? Boss!
All right! Climb! Climb!
よし！上れ！上れ！
いけー！
開く 奇跡の軌道！
The miraculous path opens!
いけ！
Go! Take down the king!
王を…
王を殺れ！
よせ！やめろ！
No!
Stop!
やー！なんで… なんでじゃ！
What!?
ああ… クッソー！
Dammit!
もう少しだったのに
He was almost there!
カイジさん…
Kaiji!
店長　今の動きは…
Boss!
Why did it move like that!?
なんで あんなことが？
I don't know.
分からん
だが１つだけ確かなことは
But I'm sure of one thing.
It's backwards.
逆なんだ
は？
The tilt is reversed. It's not leaning forward, it's leaning back.
傾きが逆
手前ではなく奥へと傾いている
そ… そんなバカな
That's impossible!
It's showing the tilt set to +7 forward!
表示はプラス７
手前傾斜の表示ですが
Where have you been keeping the remote?
管理はどうなっている？
In a desk in the office.
事務所の机の中です
Could he have reversed the wiring?
まさか… 配線を換えられたか
配線を… 換えた？
The wiring?
He switched it?
I don't know how he did it...
どうやってかは分からんが
But Kaiji must have snuck into the office and reversed the wiring in the remote!
カイジが事務所に忍び込み
リモコンの配線を逆にして
マイナスがプラスに
表示されるように仕掛けた
To make it display a plus rather than a minus!
し… しかし 忍び込まれたような
形跡はありません
But there were no signs of him sneaking in!
ここまでミスを重ねてきた お前の
言うことなど 信じられるものか！
You've fucked up how many times now? Why should I believe you?
て… 店長
(物音)
Boss!
ああ… １玉400円が
Oh man, those are worth 400 yen each!
400 each... Excuse me!
400円が　ああ…
すいません　ありがとう
What is it?
どうしました？
見ろ
Look!
The balls are all rolling in the same direction!
た… 玉が 同じ方向に…
All of them...
全体…
え？
リモコンの配線を換えたとか
He didn't just rewire the remote!
そんな小細工じゃない
や… 奴は
He actually tilted it!
傾けてきた
このフロア全体を
He tilted the whole floor!
傾けてきた！
The floor!?
フロア… 全体？
The whole floor?
手前に傾いた３段目のクルーンを
To tilt the third tray back to level...
奥側に傾けるため
か… 傾けたというのは…
How'd he tilt it?
まだ分からんのか！ビルだ！
Don't you get it? It's the building!
このビルそのものだ！
He tilted the whole fucking building!
そ… そんな　そんなこと…
No way!
Is that even possible!?
可能なんですか？
I've heard of a way!
聞いたことがある
地震などで傾いたビルを
It's used to repair buildings which tilt after a quake!
土台から持ち上げて
補修する工事のやり方があると
傾いたビルを平らにできるなら
And if you can make a tilting building level, then...
その逆 平らなビルを
傾ける方法だってあるだろう
Then you can make a level building tilt!
し… しかし
それをやろうとしたら
Wouldn't the construction be pretty obvious?
かなり大掛かりな
土木工事が必要です
でも そんな様子どころか
このビルの周りを掘り返したとか
There hasn't been any digging or heavy machinery around here in weeks.
重機が来たことすら
この数週間ありません
一体どうやって
ビルを傾けたんです？
How would he have done it?
分からん　分からん
I don't know.
I don't know! I just know he tilted it!
だがともかく 奴は傾けた！
He did some kind of serious work!
その大掛かりな土木工事クラスの
何かを使って！
て… 店長
Boss!
うるさい　どけ！
Shut up! Out of my way!
That pain in the ass!
邪魔だ　邪魔だ！
て… 店長！
Boss!
フッ 醜くイラつきおって
He looks pissed off. Maybe he figured it out.
さすがに奴も
異変に気づいたかのう
傾斜の逆転に
But even if he knows about the tilt, he doesn't know the rest!
だが気づきは その結果まで
He doesn't know why it's tilting!
なぜ傾いたかは分からない
He can't even imagine it!
想像の外
The idea of tilting the building is too farfetched for him to get it!
大体 ビルそのものを
傾けるっていう発想自体が
普通じゃない
異様 破格で訳の分からん着想
He can't figure it out!
A normal person will never figure it out!
ましてや その仕掛けに至っては
凡人じゃ想像もつかねえ
バカバカしいというか
奇想天外というか…
It's too unusual, too bizarre!
不要なんだ 工事は
We don't need to build anything.
あ？工事が不要？
We don't?
Heaven... No, the earth is on our side.
天が… いや
地が味方したと言うべきか
We sink it on that side.
沈むんだ
何もしなくても あの辺りは
Sink it?
沈む？
偶然なんだが
あのカジノの近くにあるビルが
I just happened to hear that one of the buildings nearby is being repaired.
補修工事してるって話を
聞いたんだ
That's my key to beating the Bog.
まさに沼攻略の
決定打となる情報さ
決定打？
そのビルは
The key?
The repair is to fix a settling problem.
地盤沈下で傾いたビルを
元に戻す工事をしてたんだ
なっ… 沈むってのは
そういうことか
So that's what you mean by sinking!
早い話 あのカジノ周辺の地盤は
ヤワいんだ
To skip to the point, the earth around that casino is soft.
I see.
なるほど　しかし だから何？
How does that help us?
It doesn't matter how soft it is, it still takes a lot of effort to make it sink!
いくらヤワいったってな
地面ってやつは
ちょっとやそっとの力で
沈むもんやない！
10トン
え？
Ten tons.
いや 20トンなら？
は？
No, twenty.
20トンの重みが ビルの片側に
乗っかったらどうだ？
What if we put a 20-ton weight on one side of the building?
沈んでかねえか？
じわじわと 片側が
Will it sink? Just a little bit?
そ… そりゃまあ 確かに
I guess...
But do you realize how big a 20-ton weight is gonna be?
だがな 簡単に20トンって言うが
具体的に どれくらいのもんか
分かってんのか？
That's a thousand sandbags!
10キロの土嚢にして2000個だぞ
エレベーターを使うにしろ
階段を使うにしろ
It doesn't matter if you have an elevator or not, that'll take a lot of time and effort.
大変な労力と時間がかかる
You think they won't notice you doing that?
そんな作業を
奴らが気づかないと思うか？
It's too unrealistic!
非現実的すぎだ！
I'm not using sand.
砂じゃない
は？
You're not using sand?
砂じゃない？
I'm using water.
水だ
水？
Water?
水なら運ばずとも
蛇口をひねれば出てくる
I don't need to move water, just turn on a faucet.
That building has plenty of empty rooms.
いくらでも
あのカジノが入ったビル
空き部屋がいくつもある
傾けたい方向に位置する部屋を
借りて 並べるんだ
I rent rooms on the right side of the building and just line 'em up.
１立方メートルの
ビニール水槽を20個
Twenty square-meter vinyl water tanks.
The tanks can be folded up and put in cardboard boxes.
水槽は畳んで段ボールに入れ
We have movers bring them in.
引っ越しを装って
その部屋へ運び入れる
Then we line them up along the wall and fill 'em up.
部屋に持ち込んだら水槽を広げ
傾けたい側に並べ
部屋の水道を総動員して
水を入れる
Eight hours is enough to fill them all.
８時間もあれば
20個すべて いっぱいになる
８時間なら カジノで毎日１回ある
That's short enough where we can avoid the daily balance check of the roulette wheel.
ルーレットの水平チェックも
かいくぐれる
結果 人知れず並ぶ
So we can do it without being noticed.
並ぶ 20個！
Line up twenty!
荷重20トンの水のサイコロ！
Twenty tons of water dice!
簡単かつ現実的な話だろ？
Sounds a bit more feasible now, huh?
ほんまや！
まったく そのとおりや
That's it!
Kaiji! Your crazy plan is paying off!
カイジ君　あんた
見事に あのバカげた奇策を
現実化した！
Now all you need to do is hit the jackpot!
あとは当てるだけ
Hit the jackpot!
当てるだけや！
Go for it!
いけいけ！
今日はマジで気配があるぜ
It really feels like today's the day!
入る 入る！
You can get it in!
入る！入る！入る！入る！
カイジ君
Kaiji!
奇想天外　起死回生
A miraculous reversal of fortune!
常識を超えたカイジの奇策
Kaiji's unconventional plan pays off!
再び開くか
It opens again!
逆転の軌道
The road to reversal! The path to a miracle!
奇跡への道！
The Kaiji S2 DVD box volume 1 will go on sale September 21st!
This is the bar Surpass in Kichijoji, Tokyo.
In the back of the bar is the grave of Shigeru Akagi, hero of Fukumoto's masterpiece Akagi!
It's a pilgrimage site for Akagi fans.
This is Surpass in Kichijoji, where FKMT fans gather!
If you're in Kichijoji, come zawa zawa with us!